

## Profile

I am Divya Chourasiya, a Junior Software Developer with 1.8+ years of experience in IT. Holding a B.Tech in Computer Science, I specialize in various technologies such as Node.js, JavaScript, React.js, SQL, MongoDB, Microservices, AWS, and more. I have effectively overseen projects across my career, encompassing requirements analysis, solution design, delivery, support, research, and comprehensive documentation.

# Employment History

MERN Stack at Infograins Software Solution Pvt. Ltd, Indore

May 2023 — Present

- Developed on PBM Coin Utilizing the Blockchain to Power the Future of Trade Finance.PBM Coin is powered by blockchain technology to provide a decentralized marketplace whereby businesses can tap on the different financial solutions.
- Skilled in a wide-ranging tech stack encompassing Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB proficiency in JavaScript (ES6) and Restful API.
- Expertise in integrating payment gateways, particularly Stripe, through Node.js, ensuring secure transactions.
- Proficient in developing SMS and email services, as well as implementing Google reCAPTCHA and two-factor authentication and track IP address.

### MERN Stack at Synetal Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Indore

January 2022 — April 2023

- Proficient in a diverse range of technologies including NodeJS, Web API 2.0,MySQL, JavaScript, Express.JS and ES6,HTML,CSS and MongoDB, Soap API, Restful API, AWS Code-commit, API Gateway, Merge, Code-pipeline and Micro-service.
- Experienced in SOAP and Restful API development, with a strong track record of integrating systems such as Vodafone services and QR code functionality using AWS buckets..
- Developed payment gateways using Node.js for Kina Bank,
  Stripe, and Razor-pay, demonstrating skill in secure transaction processing.
- Worked on whats-app bot create with twilio in Node.JS.
- Developed product using AWS functionality Code-commit, API Gateway, Code-pipeline and Micro-service and Lambda functions

## Education

BM college of Technology Engineering (RGPV University), Bachelors in Computer Science, Indore

August 2017 — June 2021

#### **Details**

1007 /9 Nehru Nagar Indore Madhya Pradesh, 452001 Indore, India Indore, 452001 India +918349748883

divyachoursiya1007@gmail.com

Date of birth

17.09.1998

Nationality

Indian

#### Links

Linkedin Github

#### **Skills**

Node.js

React.js

**JavaScript** 

NOSQL/MongoDb

Express.js

Rest full Web API 2.0

SOAP API

Html

Css

Jquery

Microservice

Serverless Framework

AWS Lambda

ES<sub>6</sub>

S3 Bucket

AWS CodeCommit

# **★** Personal Projects

# E-commerce-Project (08/2022 - 09/2022), Indore

August 2022 — October 2022

1. Learning Project backend using Node.JS and Frontend React.JS https://ecomm-reacts.herokuapp.com/

# Doctor's Online Appointment Booking System (01/2022 - 03/2022), Indore

January 2022 — March 2022

- 1. Doctor's Appointment Management service create Rest full API.
- 2. Doctor's conference system which manages the data of various user such as messages Using technologies like Nodes, Web API 2.0,MySQL, JavaScript, Express.JS and ES6,HTML,CSS and MongoDB, Soap API,Restful API

Mail Service SMTP

GitLab/Github

Sequelize ORM

SMS Service Tiwilo

Google Capture And Two Factor Authentication

PostgreSQL